<?xml version='1.0' encoding='ASCII'?>
<block>
  <name>ThumbDV</name>
  <key>ThumbDV</key>
  <category>hpsdr</category>
  <import>execfile("/home/tom/.grc_gnuradio/ThumbDV.py")</import>
  <make>ThumbDV($DVmode, $DeviceID)</make>
  <param>
    <name>DV Mode</name>
    <key>DVmode</key>
    <value>0</value>
    <type>enum</type>
    <option>
      <name>DSTAR</name>
      <key>0</key>
    </option>
    <option>
      <name>DMR</name>
      <key>1</key>
    </option>
  </param>
  <param>
    <name>Device Serial ID</name>
    <key>DeviceID</key>
    <value>'/dev/ttyUSB0'</value>
    <type>string</type>
  </param>
  <sink>
    <name>inp</name>
    <type>float</type>
    <vlen>1</vlen>
    <optional>0</optional>
  </sink>
  <sink>
    <name>msg_in</name>
    <type>message</type>
    <optional>0</optional>
  </sink>
  <source>
    <name>out</name>
    <type>float</type>
    <vlen>1</vlen>
    <optional>0</optional>
  </source>
  <source>
    <name>msg_out</name>
    <type>message</type>
    <optional>0</optional>
  </source>
<doc>
~/.grc_gnuradio/ThumbDV.py

This block is both the encoder and decoder for a DVSI 3000
USB stick based Thumb digital vocoder from Northwest Digital Radio (NWDR).
The streaming input and output ports consists of floating points at an
8 Ks/s rate. 

The compressed audio samples (input to decoder, output from encoder)
are PMT (polymorphic) message ports of array[0..8] of unsigned bytes.

The audio waveform input and output ports are 32-bit floats at 8 ks/s
streaming.

Audio input goes to the encoder which produces the message output.
Message input goes to decoder which produces the audio output.

This block also contains the common I/O for the USB stick, selecting the device
based on the string (e.g. /dev/ttyUSB0 typical on Ubuntu, different on other
systems) and communicating to the stick.  All of the I/O for both encoding
and decoding is done through one serial port, and this module figures out
which stick responses need to go to the encoder and which to the decoder.
 
If the decoder function is not needed, don't hook up the msg_in port and
the float out port.  If the encoder function is not needed, don't hook up the
msg_out and the float inp port.

Parameters:
DVmode - the mode of the encoder and decoder (DSTAR or DMR). DMR is same
as P25 half-rate. Both encoder and decoder must be set to the same mode
(USB stick hardware limitation). Mode choices include vocoder rate, forward
error correction settings, etc.

DeviceID - a string representing the device - e.g.  /dev/ttyUSB0 is likely for
Ubuntu, other operating systems will have a different format.

</doc>
<grc_source></grc_source>
</block>
